JONATHAN WRIGHT

Lead Business Analyst +1-921-389-0182 • name@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/jonwrightjr • Dallas, TX

Summary

I am an experienced Business Analyst with a strong technical background and great project management skills. I am able to work on multiple projects at the same time, which over the years at Network Solutions have lead to eight-digit efficiencies for the business. Furthermore, I immensely enjoy the process of deriving critical business insights using analytics, and then supporting or directly managing the efficiency implementation projects. My ability to move from analysis or leading a team of analysts to supporting or leading the actual project is something that could help further accelerate the velocity of work at Ion Insights.

Skills

Business; Budgeting · Financial Analysis · Project Management · Stakeholder Management · Business Strategy

Technology: Excel · VBA · SQL · QuickBooks · Power BI · Tableau · Python

Experience

Network Solutions LLC Dallas, TX

Lead Business Analyst & Project Manager

2019 - Ongoing

- Created new strategies to manage \$2 million of accounts at risk, resulting in an increase of 4% in revenue in 6 months.
- · Led the effort to deploy an automated time & expense reporting system for more than 90 onsite and offsite personnel across 3 locations.
- · Oversaw the budget and schedule of a project to recruit, hire, and train 150 new employees at five new locations.

Senior Business Analyst 2017 - 2019

- Through an improved pricing model, increased gross revenue of 15% in 2018 compared to 2017 with no change to fixed costs.
- Reduced warehouse processing time by 30% in just 3 months while industry norm is 10 months.
- Achieved project milestones and deliverables with an internal and external team of 10+ analysts.

Lauzon Dallas, TX
Business Analyst 2013 - 2016

Lauzon is a 30-year-old limited company in the printing and packaging field with over 150 employees.

- Prepared 2016 Budget with Variance analysis to prior years.
- Assisted merger in advanced electronics space, identifying synergy opportunities of \$ 60 M.
- Reduced IPS (Customer Issues) by 2.2% while impacting merely 3% of GMV.
- Designed and maintained 10+ data integration jobs.

Education

University of Wisconsin

M.Sc. in Finance

University of Wisconsin

Wisconsin

BBA: Business, Supply Chain Management

2008 - 2012

Courses & Certificates

PMI Professional in Business Analysis (PBA) — PMI, 2019

Certified Associate in Project Management (CAPM) — PMI, 2018

High-Dimensional Data Analysis — Harvard, 2017

Interests & Hobbies

Giving back to my community

With my two kids, I spend at least one day each month volunteering.

Horse-riding & spending time in nature

Recharging during the weekend is vital for leading a high-performing team.

Developing my team into star analysts

Not only is it very satisfying, but it is also the highest value-add of any leader.

Powered by CY Enhancy